

Technologist, Problem Solver, and Philomath

359 W Glade Rd • Palatine, IL • 60067 **CELL** (703) 209-1090 • **E-MAIL** allenthesun@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/allensun

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack agile developer with over 17 years combined experience with software development who has worked on challenging projects from computer games to web applications for government contracts. I'm an energetic self-starter who loves to learn, solve problems, and challenge myself. I want to be a part of something fresh and innovative. I have excellent analytical, organizational, and creative skills with an avid attention to detail.

SKILLS

Programming Languages (in order of recent experience)

- Typescript (4 years) SQL (10 years) HTML (10 years) CSS (10 years) SQL (10 years)
- Python (3 years)C# (10 years)JavaScript/jQuery (10 years)C++ (8 years)

Technologies (in order of recent experience)

- React (2 years) NodeJS/Express (2 years) Postgres (3 years) REST (6 years) GCP (2 years)
- dbt (1 year)BigQuery (1 year)Angular (2 years)NET Core (2 years)AWS (1 year)
- MVC w/ Razor (8 years)
 Azure (2 years)
 EpiServer (2 years)
 Crystal Reports (2 years)

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Engineer - Unstoppable Domains

Remote — April 2021 – March 2023

- Worked on the data team and set up data pipelines using Airflow, dbt, and BigQuery
- · Set up initial star schema data models which improved report building and data transparency
- Worked on the E-commerce team to add features to customer facing website which sells web3 blockchain domain names
- Added tax collection functionality to checkout flow using TaxJar which allowed company to collect taxes and meet compliance
- Improved performance of domain search by speeding up backend API by 20%
- Implemented audit logs in Postgres which allowed for tracking of historical data
- Engineering stack was React/NodeJS/Express/Typescript/Postgres hosted in GCP

Principal Engineer - KeHE Distributors

Naperville, IL — October 2020 – April 2021

- Worked as a tech lead on an enterprise web application for managing products
- Application was developed with Angular 11 front end and .NET Core 3 back end hosted in AWS Lambda microservices

Principal Engineer - American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons

Rosemont, IL — October 2018 – October 2020

- Worked as a tech lead on a project to replace SSO for all AAOS applications with PingOne for Customers utilizing both SAML and OIDC/OAuth 2.0
- Converted AAOS' main website from Ektron CMS to EpiServer which involved data migration and creating new components in EpiServer using C# and .NET MVC (www.aaos.org and www.aaosnow.org)
- Responsible for maintenance and support of legacy applications built using ASP.Net web forms as well as newer applications using Angular 6+
- Built an educational video portal site using EpiServer (videos.aaos.org)
- Managed and coached two other developers (one senior level and one junior level)

Allen Sun Page 2

EXPERIENCE (cont.)

Software Architect/Principal Software Engineer - CACI, Inc.

Chantilly, VA — December 2011 - July 2017

- Responsible for designing and developing a robust .NET 4.0 MVC web application for the DIA utilizing HighView, Oracle, SQL Server, Entity Framework, Kendo UI, Telerik Reporting and RESTful web services
- Managed stand-ups, sprint planning meetings, and retrospectives as Scrum Master
- Worked on internal tool development for improving developer productivity

Senior Software Engineer - Network Security Systems Plus, Inc.

Falls Church, VA — February 2009 – December 2011

- Led a group of 6 developers in the design and creation of a workflow based ASP.NET application in C# and VB in support of a prime contract for the Department of the Navy
- Developed a windows service for generating scheduled reports using Crystal Reports
- Developed a RESTful web service to encrypt and decrypt files using AES
- Designed and developed a module for creating dynamic data-driven web controls

QA Analyst - Menusoft

Springfield, VA — December 2008 – February 2009

- Responsible for product testing of restaurant POS software
- Scripted test cases with Rational Test

VBA/Access Developer – Palisades Media Group

Santa Monica, CA —July 2006 – April 2008

 Responsible for developing Access databases and Excel VBA scripts to handle importing data and generating reports

Contract Web Developer – Aesthetic Laser Concepts

Beverly Hills, CA — August 2004 – May 2006

 Designed and created websites for a cosmetic laser surgery company to promote online presence and to generate leads

MMORPG Game Designer, Ninth Domain (unreleased) - Tektonic Studios

Oakhurst, CA — April 2003 - January 2004

- Worked on an original IP fantasy massively multiplayer online game
- Designed and scripted combat system, abilities, spells, and character advancement in Python

PROJECTS

Hedera Hashgraph Hackathon – PromiseMe App and API (2020)

AAOS Hackathon – OrthoRun mobile game (2019)

AWARDS &

Certified Scrum Master – Scrum Alliance (2013)

CERTIFICATIONS Technology & Innovation Award – NSSPlus (2009)

EDUCATION

DigiPen Institute of Technology - Real Time Interactive Simulation

Redmond, WA — 2000-2002

University of Illinois - Computer Science

Urbana-Champaign, IL — 1996-1999

William Fremd High School - Valedictorian

Palatine, IL — 1992-1996